

Sushmita Manche

Details

Bengaluru

India

7021749532

sushmita17manche@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Indian

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

17-09-1995

Mumbai

Links

<u>linkedin.com/in/sushmitamanche/</u>

Skills

Fast Learner

Adaptability

Leadership

Interpersonal Skills

Decision Making

Critical thinking and problem solving

Creativity

Ability to Work in a Team

Ability to Multitask

Effective Time Management

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Communication Skills

Partnership Management

Business Process Improvement

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft Office

Computer Skills

Hobbies

Travelling, Cooking, Binge-Watch

Profile

Experienced and self-motivated finance operations manager with 5+ years of industry experience in direct sales and marketing, finance operations, leadership, NBFC partnership management, and business product integration.

Providing a proven track record of working closely with sales, FinOps, finance, and NBFC partners to meet goals and give the best payment alternatives at the best prices with the best services, resulting in higher revenue gains and a positive customer and partner experience.

I have a flexible and growth-oriented mentality that allows me to broaden my area of competence over time, and I am willing to master new skills and topics.

I take initiative, plan and execute, and keep the leader/manager and others informed, but I can generally follow-through on major priorities by overcoming hurdles and attaining goals.

Employment History

Manager Finance Operations, upGrad.com, Bengaluru

APRIL 2022 - PRESENT

- Monitor the daily team KPI's, targets and ensure they are met by defining financial goals and objectives for them.
- Handling escalations, urgent questions, and concerns about payment closures from Sales team, Refund, NBFC's.
- Addressing payment issues for learners by collaborating with cross-functional teams such as tech support, product management, revenue, and lending partners.
- Direct engagement with business heads/directors/AD's/VH of sales, product, financing partners for payment closures and payment options on portal to boost revenue & provide better services,
- Strong experience working with people from many cultures and states Pan India
- Managing end-to-end coordination of 10 lending Partners (NBFC) such as EMI plans integration, business strategies, handling escalations in terms of tech difficulties, service challenges involving learners, internal teams such as sales, refunds, product, and lending partners
- Worked on the end-to-end planning, development, and launch of a important product features with other cross-functional internal and external stakeholders
- Have strong product understanding of a payments-oriented platform capable of on boarding businesses/merchants.
- Excellent at writing process & product requirements for new features and improvements. Have performed in-depth requirements gathering, documentation, analysis, and product development.

Assistant Manager Finance Operations, upGrad.com, Bengaluru

APRIL 2021 - APRIL 2022

- Transferred to the Bangalore upGrad office to manage the Fin Ops team.
- Monitor the daily KPIs and targets and ensure they are met by defining financial goals and objectives for them.
- Addressing payment issues for learners by collaborating with cross-functional teams such as tech support, product management, revenue, and lending partners.
- Weekly direct interaction with business heads/directors/AD's/VH of sales, product, and financing partners for payment closures and payment options to have smooth process, increase in revenue generation and services.

Languages

| English | |
|---------|--|
| Telugu | |
| Hindi | |
| Marathi | |

- I was successful in meeting team goals.
- Handling escalations, important questions, and concerns about payment closures from Sales Admission Counselors
- End-to-end coordination of 6 lending Partners (NBFC) such as EMI plans integration, business strategies, addressing escalations in terms of tech concerns, service challenges between learners, internal teams such as sales, refunds, product, and lending partners
- Payment Page Auditing and EMI plan activation for the launch of a new programmes by communicating with cross-functional teams and lending partners within specified deadlines.

Senior Associate Finance Operations, upGrad.com, Mumbai

SEPTEMBER 2020 - APRIL 2021

- Monitor the daily KPIs and targets and ensure they are met by defining financial goals and objectives for them.
- Managing escalations, crucial questions and issues from Sales Admission Counselors, social media, refunds and student support teams.
- Payment plans verification and validation at the program level on the website/Mobile App
- Produced an analysis report on program level payment plans improvements & successfully fixed the payment plans on the website.
- Fixed payment issues for learners by collaborating with cross-functional teams such as tech support, product management, revenue, and lending partners.
- Sales and Fin Ops teams were trained on the balance closure process and payment options.
- I received praise from learners and upper management for my exceptional effort and service.

Associate Finance Operations, upGrad.com, Mumbai

JANUARY 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2020

- Closing balances for learners who have been enrolled by admission counselors
- Following up on prompt inquiries by phone, video conferences, and email writings
- Advising learners on the optimal payment method to choose depending on the financial profile provided by the learners (CIBIL, Documents required, Income, Average banking)
- Guiding learners through the payment site to select payment methods, processing EMI applications, negotiating with lending partners for EMI approval, and post-approval procedure
- Every week, I meet or surpass payment closure targets & was a top performer.
- Providing feedback to management on the payment portal and lending partners' application journeys and planning strategies in order to have improvements.
- In addition to the foregoing, After two months, I trained the six interns on the collecting procedure and oversaw the interns on a daily basis to ensure they met their goals.
- 0% Internal team and learner errors or escalations against me
- Worked with cross-functional teams such as tech support, revenue, and loan partners to resolve payment issues for learners

Corporate Sales Leader, Valour Organization, Mumbai & Chennai

OCTOBER 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2019

- I learned how to train the trainee.
- Trained and Developed 20+ business associates into Face to Face sales & marketing
- Effective territory planning for the team every start of the week

- Managed Admin, HR and Sales role on daily basis for 3 months when company shifted to Chennai post 1 year experience
- Provided In-house and on field training to business associates on daily basis
- As a Best performer, got an opportunity to work in 7 different cities for a 7-10 days
- Also, got an opportunity to network, share knowledge and train the performers across different sister companies in different states.
- Experienced in generating revenue from customers across metro and non metro cities.

Business Associate - F2F Sales, Valour Organization, Mumbai

SEPTEMBER 2017 - OCTOBER 2017

- Generating Leads and potential customers on daily basis by doing face to face marketing and concept based sales.
- Experience into B2C & B2B sales campaigns
- Best Performer across the team & got promoted as a Corporate Sales Leader post 1 week as per the set targets.

Education

Bachelors of Engineering in Information Technology, Saraswati College of Engineering, Navi Mumbai

2013 - 2017

H.S.C, Guru Nanak Khalsa College of Arts Science & Commerce, Mumbai 2011 - 2013

S.S.C., I.E.S.V.N.SULE GURUJI ENGLISH MEDIUM SECONDARY SCHOOL, Mumbai

2001 - 2011

Courses

Business Analysis Foundation, IIBA-LinkedIn

FEBRUARY 2023 - FEBRUARY 2023